You've probably heard of the abbreviation LGBTQQIAAP2S
如果你曾经听说过LGBTQQIAAP2S
or some forms of that, but how many of the words
或者是一些类似的其他形式的缩写
behind these letters, do you actually understand?
这些字母背后的意思，你真的知道吗？
Most people understand the first four but things get a little
很多人只知道前四个字母LGBT的意思
tricky after that, so let's start with the basics.
却对后面的字母模棱两可，因此我们从最基础的说起
The term lesbian refers to a woman
女同性恋者这个词语指代的是
who is sexually attracted to other women.
一位会被其他女性吸引的女性
and the term gay refers to people
而同性恋者这个词则指代
who are attracted to members of the same sex,
那些会被相同性别的人吸引的人
most often, men who are attracted to other men.
通常是指男性被另一位男性吸引
A bisexual person feels sexual attraction to both men and women.
双性恋对男性和女性都会产生性吸引
The term transgender describes a person
而变性者则是形容一个人
who identifies mentally and emotionally as a gender
在精神上和情感上把自己定义为
that does not match their biological gender.
一个与之生理性别不同的性别
It also functions as an umbrella term for trans people,
与此同时，变性者也是一个总称
including transwomen, transmen and transsexual.
包括女变性者、男变性者和换性者
The term is describing people who alter themselves physically
这个术语用来描述
through surgery or hormone therapy to align
通过手术或者激素疗法转换性别
their physical bodies with their gender identity.
使其生理性别与心理性别相同的人
Please keep in mind that gender and sexuality are not the same.
请注意，生理性别和心理性别并不一样
A phrase to help remember this distinction
有句俗话可以便于你记住这种差距
is sexual orientation is who you go to bed with,
性取向是你与谁上床
and gender identity is who you go to bed as.
而性别认同是你以怎样的角色上床
That brings us to the first confusing letter Q.
由此，我们到了颇为疑惑的字母Q
This one letter actually stands for all of the letters together.
这个字母其实代表了之前所有的字母的集合
Queer, it's another umbrella term,
酷儿，是另一个总称
and it applies to all LGBT+ people as a whole
它适用于所有LGBT+群体
and is a lot shorter and easier to say than LGBTQQIAAP2S.
并且比LGBTQQIAAP2S要简短许多
Some people also use queer as a general term to identify
有些人也用同性恋这个词来形容自己
themselves that they don't feel that they fit into
感觉无法融入
a certain letter or group.
特定的字母或群体之中
The next Q also covers a large group,
下一个Q也包含了很广泛的群体
but this one stands for questioning.
但是这个Q意思是疑性恋
Just like it sounds, the term questioning describes people
就像它的字面意思，疑性恋是指
who are wondering whether or not they belong in the queer community
那些不确定自己是否属于同性恋群体
or are still questioning
或者仍在纠结于
their gender identity or sexual preference.
自己的性别认定或者性别取向
I stands for intersex, intersex people are born with or
字母I，代表双性别者
develop genitals with ambiguous sexual characteristics
双性别者与生俱来或后天发育模糊的性别特征
because of the chromosomal or hormonal abnormalities.
这是因为他们的染色体或激素异常
Doctors will often choose a gender for intersex babies
医生通常为双性婴儿选择一种性别
and assign that gender through surgery soon after birth.
然后在出生后不久用手术去除另一性征
It should also be noted that the outdated term hermaphrodite
还应该注意的是，过时的术语“雌雄同体”
is considered offensive and should not be used to describe
是被认为有攻击性的
these types of people.
这个词不应该用来形容这一类人
The first A in this litany of letters stands for asexual
在这一串字母中，第一个字母A是指无性恋
of person who feels only romantic attraction,
无性恋者仅仅会感受到情感层面的浪漫吸引
not sexual attraction, towards any gender.
不会感受到对于性方面的吸引，不论来自哪个性别
This is not to be confused with a gender which
请不要把无性和一种
describes people who identify as neither male nor female.
认为自己既不是女性也不是男性的性别认知混淆在一起
The second A doesn't necessarily describe queer people at all.
第二个A其实压根并不指代酷儿或性少数群体
It stands for ally, the person who supports
它代表同盟/伙伴——那些支持
the causes of the LGBT+ community without identifying
LGBT+群体的诉求
as queer or LGBT+ themselves.
而自己并不是LGBT+群体的人
Ideally, this term would include everyone
理想地说，这个词将包括
in the world who isn't an LGBT+.
世界上所有非LGBT+群体的人
But we're not quite there yet.
但是我们目前还没到那一步
P is for pansexual.
字母P代表泛性恋者
Members of this sexuality are attracted to other people,
这个性向的人会被其他人吸引
regardless of gender.
不管对方的性别是什么
This term is broader than bisexual, which limits attractions to
这个术语比双性恋者更广泛，因为双性恋限制了性吸引力
adjust to male and female. Pansexuality is also often
在对象是男性或女性之间调整
related to an attraction to another person's personality.
而泛性恋者通常是被另一个人的个性或人格吸引
And finally, two S stands for two spirit.
最后，两个S指代双灵人
This native American term applies to people
这是美国本土的词汇
who display both female and male qualities.
适用于那些同时表现出男性和女性的特质
whether in their personality, sexuality or gender identity.
不论是他们的个性、性征或者性别认同上
And that's the queer alphabet.
以上所有，就是性少数群体字母缩写的意义
Even if you don't fit into any of these categories,
即使你自己并不属于以上任何一种类别
I hope that you now have a better understanding of the people
我希望你现在对你周围的人们多一分理解
around you or even yourself and can work toward
甚至你自己也可以朝着
being a better ally for queer people throughout the world.
做全世界性少数群体的同盟，支持他们而努力
爱
就是